<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clarion Music Society: NYC's Period-Instrument Orchestra Since 1957</title>
    <description>The Clarion Society was founded in 1957 by pioneering musicologist and conductor Newell Jenkins. In the 1970s, it became one of the first New York ensembles to begin performing on period instruments. Today, the Clarion Society is comprised of the renowned Clarion Orchestra, and the celebrated vocal ensemble, the Clarion Choir.</description>
    <link>http://clarionsociety.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://clarionsociety.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 13:05:08 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 13:05:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mozart Grand Mass in C Minor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Clarion Orchestra, Choir and soloists join for a performance of Mozart’s largest-scale choral work, the Mass in C minor.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All details will be posted here and tickets to go on sale in January 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/mozart-grand-mass-in-c-minor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/mozart-grand-mass-in-c-minor.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Viennese Classic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Principal players of The Clarion Orchestra, led by concertmaster Cynthia Roberts, perform chamber music of the Viennese Classic period: works of Mozart, Haydn, Beethoven, and Hummel. This will be the finale of the Clarion Collegium Week of master classes, which this year spotlight the Viennese classic repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/viennese-classic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/viennese-classic.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clarion Collegium Week</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;High school and college students, and young professional musicians work with principals of The Clarion Orchestra in music of the Viennese Classic period, with a special focus on the chamber music of Beethoven on original instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detailed schedule of classes and lectures will be posted here in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/clarion-collegium-week.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/clarion-collegium-week.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clarion Masked Ball</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Clarion’s Annual Masked Ball is not only a major source of support for Clarion’s music education program, but also one of the most extraordinary events on New York’s musical and social calendar. Learn to dance the Minuet and Gigue, accompanied by Baroque musicians, enjoy a world class vocal performance by the ever elegant ‘Gents of Clarion’, enjoy superb wine, a lovely dinner, and scintillating conversation in the exquisite Cosmopolitan Club.  Impossible to overdress!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/clarion-masked-ball.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/clarion-masked-ball.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Victoria</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;toms-luis-de-victoria--requiem-1608&quot;&gt;Tomás Luis de Victoria – Requiem (1608)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a great marriage of music and setting, Clarion makes its debut at The Metropolitan Museum of Art with one of the great Spanish Renaissance masterpieces, Victoria’s Requiem, in the Medieval Sculpture Hall.  The graceful proportions and delicate stonework of this 16th-century courtyard mirror the pristine beauty, elegance, and solemnity of this timeless work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;image-credit-patio-from-the-castle-of-vlez-blanco-150615-spanish-marble-of-macael-sierra-de-filabres-bequest-of-george-blumenthal-1941-41190482&quot;&gt;Image credit: Patio from the Castle of Vélez Blanco, 1506–15. Spanish, Marble of Macael (Sierra de Filabres). Bequest of George Blumenthal, 1941 (41.190.482)&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/victoria-in-the-velez-blanco-patio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/victoria-in-the-velez-blanco-patio.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All Beethoven</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;piano-concerto-no-4-in-g-major-op-58&quot;&gt;Piano Concerto No. 4 in G Major, Op. 58&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;symphony-no-6-pastoral-in-f-major-op-68&quot;&gt;Symphony No. 6 ‘Pastoral’ in F Major, Op. 68&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clarion Orchestra explores the sound world of Beethoven with two of his most beloved masterworks on historical instruments.  Brilliant young pianist Nimrod David Pfeffer performs the groundbreaking Fourth Concerto on an early 19th-century fortepiano.  The Orchestra then draws us into Beethoven’s wonderfully evocative imagery in the dramatic, programmatic symphony, the ‘Pastoral’.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/all-beethoven.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2015/all-beethoven.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rachmaninoff's Vespers</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;vespers-op-37&quot;&gt;Vespers, Op. 37&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After last season’s sold-out and widely acclaimed performances in Trinity Wall Street’s Twelfth Night Festival, the Clarion Choir reprises Rachmaninoff’s transcendent &lt;em&gt;Vespers&lt;/em&gt; to bring 2014 to a close and to celebrate the arrival of 2015.  Interspersed between the movements will be several ancient Byzantine and Kievan chants that inspired Rachmaninoff’s settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/rachminoff-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/rachminoff-winter.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Steinberg’s Passion Week</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;maximilian-steinberg--1883-1946--passion-week-premiere&quot;&gt;Maximilian Steinberg  (1883-1946) – Passion Week (Premiere)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;rachmaninoff--selections-from-liturgy-of-st-john-chrysostom-op-31&quot;&gt;Rachmaninoff – Selections from Liturgy of St. John Chrysostom, Op. 31&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The renowned Clarion Choir presents the New York premiere of a long lost Russian liturgy that was sheltered for some 70 years from the threat of communist confiscation: Maximilian Steinberg’s &lt;em&gt;Passion Week&lt;/em&gt;.  Evoking the rich harmonics of Rachmaninoff’s &lt;em&gt;Vespers&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Passion Week&lt;/em&gt; is also its stylistic complement: offering its own soaring emotions, but contrasting them with flowing meditations, prismatic reflections, and momentary revelations on the mystical themes of judgment, righteousness, mercy, and redemption.  The concert also will include select movements from Rachmaninoff’s incandescent &lt;em&gt;Liturgy of St. John Chrysostom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;live-recording&quot;&gt;Live Recording&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/clarion-music-society/steinberg-passion-week-1?in=clarion-music-society/sets/steinberg-bach-monteverdi-handel&quot;&gt;Steinberg - Passion Week, Movement 10, ‘Arise, O God’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pm-pre-concert-discussion&quot;&gt;7pm Pre-Concert Discussion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-discovery-of-passion-week&quot;&gt;The Discovery of Passion Week&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Alexander Lingas&lt;/strong&gt;, Byzantine Musicologist, City University, London,  artistic director of Cappella Romana, the choir that gave the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j7oiknuQJRY&quot;&gt;world premiere of Passion Week&lt;/a&gt; last April in Portland, OR, and in Seattle, WA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Vladimir Morosan&lt;/strong&gt;, a leading expert in the fields of Russian choral music and Orthodox liturgical music, and Founder and President of Musica Russica, the largest publisher of Russian choral music outside of Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbara Mouk&lt;/strong&gt;, whose father, conductor Igor Buketoff, was introduced to Passion Week by Dmitri Shostakovich, Steinberg’s protégé, in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarion’s artistic director Steven Fox will serve as moderator of this discussion, which will take place in the Church of St Jean Baptiste at 7pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/steinbergs-passion-week.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/steinbergs-passion-week.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vivaldi's Four Seasons</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;double-violin-concerto-in-a-minor-rv-522&quot;&gt;Double Violin Concerto in A minor, RV 522&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;concerto-in-d-major-for-lute-rv-93&quot;&gt;Concerto in D Major for lute, RV 93&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-four-seasons&quot;&gt;The Four Seasons&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vivaldi is known and loved today in large part due to the work of Clarion’s founder, Newell Jenkins, who discovered, premiered, and catalogued many of Vivaldi’s finest works. Showcasing the ever-vibrant &lt;em&gt;Four Seasons&lt;/em&gt; and the exuberant Concerto in A minor for two violins, this concert celebrates the thrilling virtuosity of The Clarion Orchestra’s soloists and spotlights a central part of the Jenkins legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/vivaldis-four-seasons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/vivaldis-four-seasons.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mozart Requiem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Clarion performs three dramatically different masterpieces from Mozart’s final year. From the symmetry and elegance of the overture to The Magic Flute, the joyousness, virtuosity, and humor of the final piano concerto, and finally to the solemnity and gravitas of the Requiem, this program displays Mozart at his technical and emotional apogee.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/mozart-requiem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://clarionsociety.org/events/2014/mozart-requiem.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
